A Guide to the Papers of William Rodgers, 1912-1940
Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
Special Collections and Archives, Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
Papers of William Rodgers, 1912-1940
Special Collections and Archives, Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
1984-33
15 items
The Rodgers papers consist of a number of bulletins of "The Colored Intercollegiate Athletic Association." Mr.Rodgers was the secretary of this group for a number of years.
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
A gift from the family of William Rodgers.
Biographical/Historical Information
William Rodgers came to the Virginia Normal and Industrial Institute in 1902 as an instructor of Manual Training and Drawing. In 1917 Mr.Rodges was appointed secretary of the university and he held that position until his retirement in 1947. Mr. Rodgers served in many committees and in 1905 became one of the coaches for the football team. He chaired the university Athelete committee from 1917-1947 and was appointed to represent the university when they joined the CIAA in 1917.
Scope and Content Information
The CIAA is one of the oldest confrences of the United States. These materials document the early years of this confrence, there are minutes and some reports. These materials are useful in defining what the African American community thought about sports, and, how these activities could be used to bring about change in the society.
The CIAA (now the Central Intercollegiate Athletic Confrence) is one of the oldest conferences in the United States. Organized in 1912, these records include some of the early minutes and bulletins which provide some of the early documentation of what were their goals and how they proceeded to implement them.
Contents List
- Printed
  - The Colored Intercollegiate Athletic Association proceedings, meetings.
    - The Twelth Annual Meeting March 10, 1923 (Box-folder 1:1)
    - The Thirteenth Annual Meeting 1924 (Box-folder 1:2)
    - The Fourteenth Annual Meeting 1925 (Box-folder 1:3)
  - The Bulletin of the colored Intercollegiate Athletic Association
    - The Bulletin 1926 (Box-folder 1:4)
    - The Bulletin 1927 (Box-folder 1:5)
    - The Bulletin 1928 (Box-folder 1:6)
    - The Bulletin 1929 (Box-folder 1:7)
    - The Bulletin 1930 (Box-folder 1:8)
    - The Bulletin 1931 (Box-folder 1:9)
    - The Bulletin 1932 (Box-folder 1:10)
    - The Bulletin 1933 (Box-folder 1:11)
    - The Bulletin 1934 (Box-folder 1:12)
    - The Bulletin 1935 (Box-folder 1:13)
    - The Bulletin 1936 (Box-folder 1:14)
    - The Bulletin 1937 (Box-folder 1:15)
    - The Bulletin 1938 (Box-folder 1:16)
    - The Bulletin 1939 (Box-folder 1:17)
    - The Bulletin 1940 (Box-folder 1:18)
    - The Bulletin 1943 (Box-folder 1:19)
    - The Bulletin 1944 (Box-folder 1:20)
    - The Bulletin 1946 (Box-folder 1:21)